Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 2003 November--Chapter edits daily prints, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 184: 1)
  Drafts and memoranda
- Current American resale (2003 September 19) all chapters (Box-folder 184: 2)
- Discarded chapter versions beginning (2003 September 20) (Box-folder 185: 1)
  Correspondence and drafts
- Men, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 186: 1)
- Tom to read, 1997 (Box-folder 186: 2)
  Articles, clippings, magazines, and transcripts of interviews
- Unlabeled, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 186: 3)
  Articles, day list, notes, and transcripts of interviews
- Men, 1997 (Box-folder 187: 1)
  Articles and papers--American Political Science Association (APSA) annual meeting
- Unlabeled, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 187: 2)
  Clippings, magazines, and notes
- Unsorted papers, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 188: 1)
  Articles, correspondence, and magazines
- Unsorted clips (2002), 1999-2001 (Box-folder 188: 2)
- Unsorted clips, 1971-2000 (Box-folder 189: 1)
  Books and magazines (folder 1 of 2)
- Inbox
  - Bushnell, Candice, 1996 (Box-folder 189: 2)
  - On-line men, 1997 (Box-folder 189: 3)
- Articles, clippings, memoranda, notes, and papers, 1993-1997
- TBE selected documents for book (2003 October 26), 2000-2004 (Box-folder 190: 1)
- Militia (folder 2 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 190: 2)
  Articles, magazine, and memoranda
- Unlabeled, 2003 (Box-folder 191: 1)
- Today's miscellany, 1998 (Box-folder 191: 2)
  Articles, correspondence, draft chapter 1, and magazine
- Bedroom to living room and back, 1998 (Box-folder 191: 3)
- Grand Old Party (GOP), 1986-1996 (Box-folder 192: 1)
  Clippings and table of contents of the rules adopted by the Republican Party of Texas
- Greenberg, Stan, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 192: 2-3)
  Includes list of participants and observers, memoranda, papers, and report relating to the New Majority conference, Virginia, 1997 January 10-12
- Homosexuals, 1996 (Box-folder 192: 4)
  Paper by Chandler Burr
- Guns, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 192: 5)
  Article, clipping, Congressional Record, magazine, and memoranda
- Review of October 1964 by David Halberstam, 1994 (Box-folder 193: 1)
- Hazing, 1997 (Box-folder 193: 2)
- Health, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 193: 3)
  Clipping and press release
- Heclo, Hugh, 1995 (Box-folder 193: 4)
  Conference paper
- Hierarchy, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 193: 5)
- Helms, Jesse, 1994 (Box-folder 193: 6)
- Heroism, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 193: 7)
- Heterodoxy, 1994 (Box-folder 193: 8)
- High-tech politics, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 193: 9)
  Article and clipping
- Hill, Anita, 1994 (Box-folder 193: 10)
- Clinton, Hillary, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 193: 11)
- Himmelfarb, Gertrude, 1995 (Box-folder 193: 12)
- Hispanics, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 193: 13)
  Article, brochure, clippings, paper, report, and voting record
- History, 1990 (Box-folder 193: 14)
- Holtzman, Marc, 1985 (Box-folder 193: 15)
  Articles about him by Thomas Edsall
- Homeless, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 193: 16)
- Homosexuality, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 193: 17)
  Book and clipping
- Honor, 1995 (Box-folder 193: 18)
- Housing, 1994 (Box-folder 194: 1)
  Clipping and report
- Hunting, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 194: 2)
  Article, book, catalog, clippings, and study
- Hurst, Bob, 1986 (Box-folder 194: 3)
- Identity, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 194: 4)
  Article, clipping, and magazine
- Men, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 194: 5)
  Articles, clippings, magazines, memoranda, and notes
- Unsorted clips (folder 2 of 2), 1993-2001 (Box-folder 195: 1)
  Articles, clippings, memoranda, and 4 mini sound cassettes, undated
- Men
  - Victims, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 195: 2)
  - Domestic violence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 195: 3)
  - Female violence, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 195: 4)
  - White violence, 1994 (Box-folder 195: 5)
  - Youth violence, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 195: 6)
    Article, clippings, magazine, and report
  - Male violence, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 195: 7)
    Article, clippings, and magazine
  - Disorder II, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 195: 8)
  - Overload disorder, 1994 (Box-folder 195: 9)
  - Media disorder, 1984 (Box-folder 195: 10)
  - Male disorder, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 195: 11)
    Articles, brochure, clippings, and magazines
- Feminist views, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 196: 1)
  Article, clippings, and magazines
- Evolutionary theories, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 196: 2)
  Article, chapter of a book? and clippings
- Father presence--Good dads, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 196: 3)
  Article, magazine, and paper
- Financial--Industry men, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 196: 4)
- Good political analyses, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 196: 5)
- Heroes, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 196: 6)
- Hyper competition, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 196: 7)
- High-tech men/Engineers--Men quantification, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 196: 8)
- Male sexuality--Polygamy, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 197: 1)
- Military sports, male adventures, and treasure seekers, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 197: 2)
- Poll data--Election, 2000 (Box-folder 197: 3)
- Resale chapter, draft, and manuscript, 2001 (Box-folder 197: 4)
- Right coalition--Culture war, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 197: 5)
- Risk, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 197: 6)
- Sexual revolution, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 197: 7)
  Articles, clippings, report, and statistical data
- Crime youth, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 198: 1)
- Disorder--Urban, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 198: 2)
- Crime
  - Crime I, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 198: 3)
    Article, clippings, and report
  - Crime II, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 198: 4)
    Articles, clipping, correspondence, report, and statistical data
- Values, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 199: 1)
  Article, magazine, newsletter, and study
- Disorder--Liberal, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 199: 2)
  Article, clipping, report, and study
- Christians, 1984-1996 (Box-folder 199: 3)
  Article, correspondence, magazine, speech, statement, and voting survey
- I.Q., 1994-1997 (Box-folder 199: 4)
  Article, clipping, magazine, memoranda, and report
- Stotz, Doug, 1997 (Box-folder 200: 1)
- Gambling, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 200: 2)
- Demographics, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 200: 3)
  Article, clipping, notes, and reports
- Men, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 200: 4)
  Articles, clippings, magazine, notes, reports, and miscellany. Includes "American Men" by Thomas Edsall and "My Fathers!" by Richard Rosenman
- Siebel--Sales information systems, 1997 (Box-folder 200: 5)
- Macdonald, Kevin, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 200: 6)
  Articles and related materials
- Newt Gingrich II, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 201: 1)
  Articles, clippings, interview, and speech
- Militia (folder 1 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 201: 2)
- Death, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 202: 1)
- Debt, 1994 (Box-folder 202: 2)
- Democrats, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 202: 3)
- Democratization, 1995 (Box-folder 202: 4)
- Demographics, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 202: 5)
- Deregulation, 1996 (Box-folder 202: 6)
- Detroit, 1993 (Box-folder 202: 7)
- Devotion, 1993 (Box-folder 202: 8)
- DiIulio, John J., Jr., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 202: 9)
- Discriminization, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 202: 10)
  Bulletin and clippings
- Disorder
  - Government, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 202: 11)
    Articles, clippings, letters, press release, and statement
  - International, 1994 (Box-folder 202: 12)
- Djerassi, Carl, 1997 (Box-folder 202: 13)
  Biographical note and miscellany
- Democratic Leadership Council (DLC), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 202: 14)
  Article, keynote address by Bill Clinton, Cleveland, Ohio, and magazine
- Dole, Robert, 1996 (Box-folder 202: 15)
- Dominance, 1995 (Box-folder 202: 16)
- Drugs, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 202: 17)
- Dulce, David, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 202: 18)
  Articles by Thomas Edsall and others, clippings, handbook, paper, and report
- Economics, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 202: 19)
- Economic policy, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 202: 20)
- Drayton, Bill, 1996 (Box-folder 202: 21)
  Article and a letter
- Cops, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 203: 1)
  Clippings and transcript of a program on public television
- Corporate
  - Disney, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 203: 2)
  - Culture, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 203: 3)
  - Loyalty, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 203: 4)
  - Strategies, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 203: 5)
- Cosmopolitan, 1997 (Box-folder 203: 6)
- Counterrevolution, 1996 (Box-folder 203: 7)
- Creativity, 1997 (Box-folder 203: 8)
  Fragment of an interview
- Critique--Men, 1996 (Box-folder 203: 9)
- Culture, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 203: 10)
- Culture war, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 203: 11)
- Cybernetic, 1976-1995 (Box-folder 203: 12)
  Article, biographical note and list of publications of Stuart Umpleby, clipping, journal, and magazine
- Dash, Leon, 1994 (Box-folder 203: 13)
- Date rape, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 203: 14)
- Day list--Thomas Edsall, 1995 (Box-folder 203: 15)
- Day list--Men, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 203: 16)
- Need to look over miscellany paper (folder 1 of 2), 1992-1999 (Box-folder 204: 1)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, magazines, memoranda, and notes
- Computers-Social change, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 204: 2)
- Confederate flag, 1996 (Box-folder 204: 3)
- Conservatives
  - General, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 204: 4)
    Article, clipping, and remark
  - Blumenthal, Sidney, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 204: 5)
  - Article, briefing, clipping, conference papers, and journal, 1985-1994
- Conservative momentum, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 204: 6)
  Article, clipping, and journal
- Contraception, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 204: 7)
- Genes, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 205: 1)
- Sexuality--Male, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 205: 2)
  Article, clipping, conference paper, magazine, and 1 photographic print depicting 2 unidentified children, undated
- Abortion, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 205: 3)
  Article, clipping, magazine, paper, polling data, press release, report, and voting record
- Labor, 1985-1997 (Box-folder 205: 4)
  Article, clipping, news release, paper, and report
- Diversity, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 206: 1)
  Articles, chart, clippings, correspondence, instructions for training and developmental professionals, interview with William Frey, news release, and paper
- PhDs, undated (Box-folder 206: 2)
  Table with number of doctorates awarded in the United States
- Suburbs, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 206: 3)
  Article, census publication, clipping, population statistics, and report
- Risk, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 206: 4)
  Article, clipping, newsletter, paper, and publication kit
- Men, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 206: 5)
  Article, clipping, conference paper, magazine, memoranda, press release, press kit, and report
- Military (Box 207)
  - Marines, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 1)
  - Navy, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 2)
  - World War II, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 3)
  - Article, clipping, paper, and presidential report, 1990-1997 (Box 207)
  - Articles, paper, and report, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 207: 4)
- Current--Tom using III (folder 3 of 3), 1993-1997 (Box-folder 207: 5)
  Articles and contact lists
- Random final '99 (Box 208)
  - Folder 1 of 3, articles, correspondence, drafts, memoranda, and notes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 208: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 3, clippings, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 208: 2)
  - Folder 3 of 3, magazines, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 209: 1)
- TBE '98 documents for book and studio, 1998 (Box-folder 209: 2)
- Need to look over--Miscellany paper (folder 2 of 2), 1974-1994 (Box-folder 210: 1)
  Oversize articles and book
- TBE '98 documents for book and studio (folder 2 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box-folder 210: 2)
  Articles and magazines
- To be incorporated into book (Box 211)
  - Folder 2 of 5, immigration, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 211: 1)
    Articles, clippings, and miscellany
  - Folder 3 of 5, magazines, 1997 (Box-folder 211: 2)
- Good clips to be sorted, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 212: 1)
- To be incorporated into book (folder 1 of 5), 1995-1997 (Box-folder 212: 2)
- Affirmative action, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 213: 1)
- Biotechnology medicine, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 213: 2)
- Businessmen, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 213: 3)
- Divorce--Marriage, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 213: 4)
  Article, clippings, memoranda, and reports
- Entertainers, cooks, religious leaders, artists, and fashion men, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 213: 5)
- Domination, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 213: 6)
- Father absence, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 213: 7)
  Clippings, magazine, and research paper
- Gender and demographics, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 213: 8)
  Article, clippings, magazine, and study
- Current--Tom using III (folder 2 of 3), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 214: 1)
- Core information regarding men. Materials quoted in book
  - Folder 1 of 3, articles, magazines, and notes, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 214: 2)
  - Interviews (Box 215)
    - Folder 2 of 3, I, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 215: 1)
    - Folder 3 of 3, II, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 216: 1)
- Men striving for dominance, 1996-2005 (Box-folder 216: 2)
- Hypercomp (Hypercompetition) (Box 217)
  - Interviews and notes, 1997 (Box-folder 217: 1)
  - Books and journals, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 217: 2)
- Politics chapter, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 217: 3)
- Clips for possible use in book, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 218: 1)
- Things may be worked into book, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 218: 2)
- Documents already quoted in book 11/98 (Box 219)
  - Folder 2 of 3, magazines, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 219: 1)
  - Folder 3 of 3, articles, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 219: 2)
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 220: 1)
- Tom to read (Box 220)
- Contact lists, interviews, memoranda, and notes, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 220: 2)
- Articles, clippings, and interviews, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 220: 3)
- To Hoover Archives (Box 221)
  - Folder 1 of 2, articles, clippings, and notes, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 221: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, magazines, 2003 (Box-folder 222: 1)
- Current--Tom using III (folder 1 of 3), 1992-1997 (Box-folder 222: 2)
- Business magazines for TBE "American Men,", 2000-2004 (Box-folder 223: 1)
- TBE sort and file these clips in BLK file (Box 224)
  - Folder 1 of 2, clippings, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 224: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, articles, magazines, and memoranda, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 225: 1)
- Men (Box 226)
  - Folder 1 of 2, clippings, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 226: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, articles and magazines, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 226: 2)
- Male success and Tailhook, VMI, Citadel, etc., 1986-1999 (Box-folder 227: 1)
- Men '04 I
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 227: 2)
  - Folder 3 of 3, magazines, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 227: 3)
  - Folder 2 of 3, articles, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 228: 1)
- Hypercomp (Hypercompetition), 1992-1999 (Box-folder 228: 2)
- Men (folder 1 of 2), 1996-2001 (Box-folder 229: 1)
- Materials cited in "Men" book March 2004, 1995-2004 (Box-folder 229: 2)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, draft chapter 2, and magazines
- Men (Box 230)
  - Folder 2 of 2, articles and magazines, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 230: 1)
  - Articles, clippings, correspondence, and magazines, 1996-2003 (Box-folder 231: 1)
- Men mailer (folder 2 of 2), 1999-2004 (Box-folder 232: 1)
- Unlabeled
  - Folder 2 of 2, articles, magazines, memoranda, and notes, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 232: 2)
  - Folder 1 of 2, clippings (early 90s), 1991-1997 (Box-folder 233: 1)
- Reproduction and social organization
  - Folder 2 of 3, clippings (early 90s), 1991-1994 (Box-folder 233: 2)
  - Folder 3 of 3, articles and magazines, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 234: 1)
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings (early 90s), 1992 (Box-folder 234: 2)
- Tom's select pile number 1--Articles, clippings, folders, magazines, and notes (Box 235)
  - Chodorow interview by phone, 1994 (Box-folder 235: 1)
  - Disorder
    - General, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 235: 2)
    - Liberal, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 235: 3)
    - Family, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 235: 4)
  - Clippings, 1992-1997 (Box 235)
  - Articles and notes, 1993-1996 (Box 235)
  - Miscellany, 1995 (Box 235)
- Disorder, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 236: 1)
- Unused preface Dec 2002 etc., 1997-2002 (Box-folder 236: 2)
  Draft of chapter 6 and notes
- Thomas Edsall, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 236: 3)
- Male female competition, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 236: 4)
- Clips rejected by TBE but saved by MDE, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 236: 5)
- Books to get II, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 236: 6)
  Amazon.com printouts and clippings
- Men mailer (folder 1 of 2), 1989-1999 (Box-folder 237: 1)
  Articles and draft chapters
- Unsorted clips from desk in studio, 1999-2003 (Box 237)
- Active file (folder 2 of 2)--Interview subjects, outline, current docs--To go through, 1997 (Box-folder 238: 1)
  Selections from American Life League's pro-life America
- Papers read by Mary for Tom to look at above average interest III
  - Folder 1 of 2 (Box-folder 238: 2)
    - Gallagher, Charles, 1994-1997 (Box 238)
      Articles and a letter to Thomas and Mary Edsall
    - Articles, clippings, magazines, notes, and pamphlets, 1989-1997 (Box 238)
  - Folder 2 of 2 (Box-folder 239: 1)
    - Immigration, 1995
      Conference papers and related materials
    - Polygamy, undated (Box-folder 239: 2)
- American Sociological Association (ASA) press conferences (Box 239)
  - "Presidential Voting,", 1995 (Box 239)
    Paper
  - "Women in the Work Place,", 1995 (Box 239)
- Articles, clippings, correspondence lecture, magazine, manuscript, papers, press release, and report, 1992-1996 (Box 239)
- Active file (folder 1 of 2)--Interview subjects, outline, current docs--To go through, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 240: 1)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, and journals
- Men, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 241: 1)
  Articles, clippings, memoranda, and notes
- Unsorted clips, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 241: 2)
- Books to get I, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 242: 1)
  Articles, clips, and magazines
- Carr, Steve, 1997 (Box-folder 243: 1)
  Articles and clipping
- Computer, undated (Box-folder 243: 2)
  Mary Edsall's day lists
- Chapter drafts, 1997 (Box-folder 243: 3)
- Children--Women, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 243: 4)
- Berlet, Chip, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 243: 5)
  Articles, clipping, newsletters, report, and miscellany
- Circumcision, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 243: 6)
- Citadel, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 243: 7)
- Cities, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 243: 8)
- Civil Rights Act, 1990 (Box-folder 243: 9)
- Civil Rights
  - General, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 243: 10)
  - Other factors on black community, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 243: 11)
  - Article and clipping, 1990
  - Materials relating to the issue of civil rights, 1989-1990
- Class, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 243: 12)
- Clinton
  - Character, 1994 (Box 243: 13)
  - Interview on "Today Show,", undated
  - State of the Union address, 1996
  - Clippings, 1993-1997
  - Democratic National Committee's fall meeting--President Clinton's address, 1993
  - Magazine, 1994
  - Report, 1996
- Clone, 1997 (Box-folder 243: 14)
- C.O. (men), 1996 (Box-folder 243: 15)
- Code words, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 243: 16)
- Coelho, Tony, 1985 (Box-folder 243: 17)
  Article by Thomas Edsall
- Cohen, William?, 1996 (Box-folder 243: 18)
- Common Cause, 1986 (Box-folder 243: 19)
  Clipping, comments, memoranda, press release, and statement
- Black business, 1989 (Box-folder 244: 1)
  Articles, clipping, and miscellany
- Black vs. Hispanic, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 244: 2)
- Black interview, 1989 (Box-folder 244: 3)
- Black mayors-- The Atlantic, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 244: 4)
  Articles by Thomas Edsall, book proposal, and correspondence
- Black men, 1968-1997 (Box-folder 244: 5)
- Bly, Robert, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 244: 6)
  Interviews and miscellany
- Bobbit, Lorena, 1993 (Box-folder 244: 7)
- Articles and book reviews by Thomas Edsall and others and letter to him, 1993 (Box-folder 244: 8)
- Brain, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 244: 9)
  Articles and miscellany
- Branch, Taylor, 1997 (Box-folder 244: 10)
- Brod, Harry, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 244: 11)
  Articles, biographical note, clippings, and a letter to Thomas Edsall
- Brown, Chris, 1995 (Box-folder 244: 12)
- Blacks--Armed services, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 245: 1)
  Clipping and reports
- Adultery, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 245: 2)
- Adventure--Men, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 245: 3)
- Adversary culture, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 245: 4)
- "American Men,", 1994 (Box-folder 245: 5)
- Anger, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 245: 6)
- Armed services, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 245: 7)
- Army scandals, 1996 (Box-folder 245: 8)
- Art, 1993 (Box-folder 245: 9)
  Information kit
- Athletics--Men, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 245: 10)
- Asian-Americans, 1990 (Box-folder 245: 11)
- Miscellany, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 245: 12)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, interview, memoranda, press release, reports, and statement
- Lynn, Richard, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 246: 1)
  Articles, letter from Mary Edsall, and list of publications
- Methodological caveats, 1992 (Box-folder 246: 2)
- Moseley, Kay, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 246: 3)
- Murray, Charles, 1988 (Box-folder 246: 4)
- Nativism, 1992 (Box-folder 246: 5)
- Patterson, Orlando, 1991 (Box-folder 246: 6)
  List of publications
- Plan master, 1992 (Box-folder 246: 7)
  Notes and outline by Mary Edsall
- Poussaint, Alvin F., 1990 (Box-folder 246: 8)
- Ruvolo, undated (Box-folder 246: 9)
- Smith, Raymond T., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 246: 10)
- Warwick, Donald, 1992 (Box-folder 246: 11)
  Course outline, list of publications, and notes
- Whiting, Beatrice, undated (Box-folder 246: 12)
  Letter from Mary Edsall
- Wacquant, Loic J. D., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 246: 13)
  Articles and notes
- Atlantic, 1995 (Box-folder 246: 14)
  Notes for an article on Bill Clinton and a letter from Thomas Edsall to Jack?
- Atwater, Lee, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 246: 15)
- Bergstrom, Theodore C., 1995 (Box-folder 246: 16)
- Peter Berkowitz, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 246: 17)
- Biology, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 246: 18)
- Gay, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 247: 1)
  Articles, clippings, letter, and report
- Kessler, Martin, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 2)
- Alker, Hayward R., Jr., 1991 (Box-folder 247: 3)
  Articles by him and others
- Anderson, Elijah, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 247: 4)
- Anthropology, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 5)
  List of faculty
- Anthony, Appiah, undated (Box-folder 247: 6)
- Behavioral norms--Western disillusion, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 7)
- Bell, Daniel, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 8)
- Polygamy, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 9)
- Christian monogamy, 1984 (Box-folder 247: 10)
- Cultural values, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 11)
- Fathes, Henry Louis, Jr., 1992 (Box-folder 247: 12)
- Glazer, Nathan, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 247: 13)
  Article and notes
- Harrison, Lawrence E., 1992 (Box-folder 247: 14)
- Herrnstein, Richard J., 1973-1992 (Box-folder 247: 15)
  Interview, letter, and notes
- Herskovits, Melville J., 1992 (Box-folder 247: 16)
- Kasarda, John D., 1992 (Box-folder 247: 17)
- Kleinman, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 247: 18)
- Levine, Robert, 1989 (Box-folder 247: 19)
  List of publication and notes
- Library--Harvard University, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 247: 20)
- Lowry, Glen, 1992 (Box-folder 247: 21)
  Article, interview, and notes
- Evolution, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 248: 1)
  Articles, clippings, magazine, and miscellany
- Crime--California, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 248: 2)
- Furstenberg, Frank F., Jr., 1987-1993 (Box-folder 248: 3)
  Articles and curriculum vitae
- Gender, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 248: 4)
  Articles, clippings, course outline, and magazine
- Family
  - Out of wedlock, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 248: 5)
  - Marriage, 1993-1996
    Clippings, letter from Thomas to Mary Edsall, and report
  - Article and clippings, 1994-1996
- Bedside Clinton, 1992 (Box-folder 249: 1)
  Guide to the new administration
- Self-in-relation, 1996 (Box-folder 249: 2)
- Reproduction--Sperm, 1996 (Box-folder 249: 3)
- Rossi, Alice, undated (Box-folder 249: 4)
- Self-actualization, 1996 (Box-folder 249: 5)
  Catalog
- Sexual revolution, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 249: 6)
- Crime--Family collapse, 1994 (Box-folder 249: 7)
  Clipping and paper
- Crime--Men, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 249: 8)
  Clippings, research data, and miscellany
- Adaptation, 1997 (Box-folder 249: 9)
- Fathers, 1984-1997 (Box-folder 249: 10)
  Articles, clippings, memoranda, paper, and press release
- Clinton legacy, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 250: 1)
  Analytical press reports about Democratic Party, articles, book, clippings, and magazine
- Monica Lewinsky and Clinton (Box 251)
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 251: 1)